Register of the Jay Lovestone papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- OFFICE FILES, 1944-1966 (Boxes 234-345)
  - 1944-1948 (Box 234)
    - Latin America, 1946-1948
    - Latin American Trade Unions, 1946
    - Lewis, John L., 1947-1948
    - Lewis, Kathryn, 1947
    - Liberal Party of New York, 1946-1948 (Box 248)
    - Licensed Agencies for Relief in Asia, 1947
    - Local Managers, 1946
    - Lovestone, Jay, 1946-1948
    - Luxembourg, 1948 (Box 249)
    - Manhattan Letter Service Company, 1946-1948
    - Marshall Plan, 1947-1948
    - Martens, R. J., 1948
    - Meskimen, John K., 1948
    - Mine, Mill and Smelter Workers, 1947
    - Miscellaneous, 1946-1948 (Box 250)
    - Miscellaneous, 1948 (Box 251)
    - Modern Review, 1947-1948
    - Montana, Vanni, 1948
    - Munger, William, 1948
    - National Catholic Welfare Conference, 1948
    - National Conference of Union Labor Legionnaires, 1946
    - Netherlands, 1947-1948
    - New York City - Municipal elections, 1945
    - New York Times, 1947-1948
    - New Zealand, 1948
    - Nineteenth Century and After, 1947
    - Norway, 1947-1948
    - Office of Military Government for Germany (U.S.), 1947-1948
    - Offie, Carmel, 1947
    - Pamphlets, 1948 (Box 252)
    - People's Voice, 1948
    - Perry, Ernestine, 1948
    - Pinski, Henry, 1947
    - Poland
      - 1947-1948
      - 1948 (Box 253)
    - Polish Information Service, 1948
    - Printed material, 1945
    - Railway labor, 1947-1948
    - Refugees Defense Committee, 1947-1948
    - Relief organizations, 1948
    - Resolutions, 1946
    - Rights of labor, 1947-1948
    - Romer, Samuel, 1948
    - Rutz, Henry
      - Correspondence, 1947
      - Correspondence, 1948 (Box 254)
      - List for CARE packages
    - Schumacher, Kurt, 1947-1948
    - Schwarzkopf, O., 1946
    - Shore, Samuel, 1946
    - Snell, Willy, 1948
    - Social Democrat, 1946
    - Southeast Asia, 1945
    - Spain - U.G.T., 1945
    - Spain - C.G.T.-U.G.T., 1946
    - Spanish Information Bureau, 1946
    - Spanish Republic, 1946
    - Special Bulletin, 1946 (Box 255)
    - Stalin, 1946
    - Stampfer, Friedrich, 1947-1948
    - Studebaker, John, 1948
    - Sweden, 1948
    - Swiss Labor Relief, 1947-1948
    - Switzerland, 1947-1948
    - Tennessee Valley Authority (TVA), 1948
    - Topalovich, Zivko, 1948
    - Trotter, J. H., 1947-1948
    - Truman, Harry S, 1947-1948
    - United Automobile Workers, 1947-1948
    - United Electrical Workers, 1946
    - United Nations, 1947-1948 (Box 256)
      - Sender, Toni
      - U.S. Representative
      - Unesco
    - Voice of America (Box 257)
    - Wallace, Henry, 1948
    - Washington (Ben Mandel), 1947-1948
    - Woll, Matthew, 1947
    - Workers Defense League, 1947-1948
    - Workers Education Bureau of America, 1947
    - World Trade Union Congress, 1945-1946
  - 1946-1953
    - Free Trade Union Committee - Accounts, auditor's reports
      - 1946-1948
      - 1949-1953 (Box 258)
  - 1949 (Box 259)
    - A - General correspondence
    - Adamczyk, A.
    - Afros, John L.
    - American Association for a Democratic Germany
    - American Council of Voluntary Agencies for Foreign Service
    - American Federation of Labor (AF of L)
      - General
      - Delaney, George
      - Executive Council reports
      - Green, William
      - International affiliates
      - International Labor Relations Committee
      - International presidents
      - Meany, George
      - Publicity
      - Southern Campaign
    - Americans for Democratic Action (Box 260)
    - Antonini, Luigi
    - Arbeiter-Wohlfahrt
    - Asian Federation of Labor
    - Australia
    - Austria
    - Austrian Federation of Unions
    - B - General correspondence
    - Balabanoff, Angelica
    - Belgium
    - Berger, Sam
    - Borchardt, Selma
    - Borochowicz, Leo
    - British Trades Union Congress
    - Brown, Harvey
    - Brown, Irving
    - C - General correspondence
    - CARE (Box 261)
    - Central Trades and Labor Council (N.Y.)
    - China
    - Christian trade unions - France
    - Clark, Mark W.
    - Clay, Lucius
    - Cohen, Harry
    - Common Cause
    - Confederation Generale du Travail - Force Ouvriere
    - Congressmen (Box 262)
    - Co-Operative Commonwealth
    - Council on Foreign Relations
    - Cultural and Scientific Conference for World Peace
    - Currie, Eve
    - Czechoslovak refugees - Acknowledgments
    - D - General correspondence
    - Dahlman, Fritz
    - Department of Labor
    - Department of State
    - Department of the Army
    - Deverall, Richard (Box 263)
    - Dohrn, Klaus (Box 264)
    - Fabian, Bela
    - Indonesia
    - Klein, Larry
    - L - General correspondence
    - Lafond, Andre
    - Lane, Tom
    - Latin America
    - Lewis, John and Kathryn
    - Liberal Party (New York)
    - Liberal Press, Incorporated
    - London Conference on Marshall Plan
      - March
      - July
    - Lovestone, Jay
    - M - General correspondence
    - McCloy, John J.
    - Mandel, Ben
    - Manhattan Letter Service
    - Meskiman, John (Box 265)
    - Mihkelson, Johannes (Box 266)
    - Montana, Vanni
    - Murphy, Ray
    - N - General correspondence
    - Netherlands
    - Nineteenth Century and After, The
    - Norway
    - Oak, Liston
    - Office of Military Government for Germany
    - Olah, Franz
    - P - General correspondence (Box 267)
    - Pamphlets
    - Pastore, Ciulio
    - Peyer, Charles
    - Poland
    - Le populaire
    - Prieto, Indalecio
    - Q - General correspondence
    - R - General correspondence
    - Reinhardt, Guenther
    - Reinlib, Samuel
    - Rockefeller Foundation
    - Romer, Samuel
    - Rowe, James
    - Roy, M. N.
    - Russia
    - Rutz, Henry
    - S - General correspondence (Box 268)
    - Saposs, David
    - Schleicher, Markus
    - Schumacher, Kurt
    - Society for the Prevention of World War III
    - Soviet Union. See Russia
    - Spain
    - Stark, Louis
    - Stern, Boris
    - Stolz, Jiri
    - Sudeten Germans
    - Sweden
    - Switzerland
    - T - General correspondence
    - Topalovich, Zivko
    - Truman, Harry S
    - U - General correspondence (Box 269)
    - U.G.O. - Berlin
    - United Nations
    - United States
    - V - General correspondence (Box 270)
    - Voice of America
    - W - General correspondence
    - Woll, Matthew
    - Workers Defense League
    - Workers Education Bureau
    - Y - General correspondence
  - 1949-1951 (Box 271)
    - Austria
    - Belgium
    - Berlin
    - Denmark, Finland, Norway, Sweden
    - Exiles (Box 272)
    - France
    - Germany
    - Germany (Box 273)
    - Greece
    - Holland
    - Luxembourg
    - National Committee for a Free Europe
    - Radio Free Europe (Box 274)
    - Switzerland
    - United States
  - 1950 (Box 275)
    - A - General correspondence
    - Adamczyk, A.
    - African General Workers Union
    - Afros, Jack
    - American Association for Democratic Germany
    - American Federation of Labor
      - General
      - Delaney, George
      - Executive Council reports
      - Green, William
      - International affiliates
      - International presidents
      - International relations
      - Meany, George
      - Publicity
    - Antonini, Luigi
    - Australia
    - Austria
    - B - General correspondence (Box 276)
    - Belgium
    - Berger, Sam
    - Borchardt, Selma
    - Borochowicz, Leo
    - British Labor Party
    - British Trades Union Congress
    - Brown, Harvey
    - C - General correspondence
    - CARE
    - Carney, Jack (Box 277)
    - Central Trades and Labor Council
    - Ceylon
    - China
    - Christian trade unions (Box 278)
    - Christian trade unions - France
    - Committee to Defend America By Aiding Anti-Communist China
    - Communist Party front organizations
    - Confederation Generale du Travail - Force Ouvriere
    - Congress for Cultural Freedom
    - Congress of Industrial Organizations (CIO)
    - Congressmen - Representatives and senators
    - Council on Foreign Relations
    - Czechoslovakia
    - D - General correspondence
    - Das, S. R. Mohan (Box 279)
    - Department of Labor
    - Deverall, Richard
    - Egypt (Box 280)
    - Great Britain. Embassy (United States)
    - International Confederation of Free Trade Unions
    - Johnson, Louis
    - McCloy, John J.
    - Marshall, George
    - Stolz, Jiri (Box 281)
    - United States
    - Woll, Matthew
  - 1951 (Box 282)
    - A - General correspondence
    - American Committee for a United Europe
    - American Council for Voluntary Agencies
    - American Federation of Labor
      - General
      - Delaney, George
      - Executive Council reports
      - Green, William
      - International Labor Relations Committee
      - International presidents
      - Meany, George
      - Seventieth Convention
    - Antonini, Luigi (Box 283)
    - Argentina
    - Australia
    - Austria
    - Austrian Federation of Labor
    - B - General correspondence
    - Beichman, Arnold
    - Belgium
    - Berger, Sam A.
    - Borchardt, Selma
    - Borochowicz, Leo
    - British Trades Union Congress
    - Brown, Harvey
    - Brown, Irving
    - C - General correspondence (Box 284)
    - CARE
    - Carney, Jack (Box 285)
    - Ceylon
    - Challenge
    - China
    - Christian trade unions
    - Circulars (Box 286)
    - Clark, Mark W.
    - Committee to Defend America by Aiding Anti-Communist China
    - Communist Party and front organizations
    - Confederation Generale du Travail - Force Ouvriere (CGT)
    - Confederazione Italiana Sindacati Lavoratori (CISL)
    - Congress for Cultural Freedom
    - Congress of Industrial Organizations (CIO)
    - Congressmen - Representatives and senators
    - Council Against Communist Aggression
    - Council on Foreign Relations
    - Cuba
    - Cuneo, Ernest
    - Cruikshank, Nelson (Box 287)
    - Czechoslovakia
    - D - General correspondence
    - Dale, Leon
    - Das, S. R. Mohan
    - Das, S. R. Mohan (Box 288)
    - Department of Labor
    - Department of State
    - Department of the Army
    - Deverall, Richard (Box 289)
      - General
      - Reports (Box 290)
        - China
        - India
        - Indochina
        - Japan
        - Korea
        - Malaya
        - Nepal
        - Pakistan
        - Philippines
        - Thailand
    - Dohrn, Klaus (Box 291)
    - Donovan, William
    - Dubinsky, David
    - E - General correspondence
    - East Africa
    - Economic Cooperation Administration
    - Economist
    - F - General correspondence
    - Finland
    - Finnish Trade Union Delegation
    - Franc-Tireur
    - France (Box 292)
    - Free China Labor League
    - Free Trade Union Center in Exile
    - Free Trade Union Committee
    - G - General correspondence (Box 293)
    - Genocide
    - German Trade Union Federation
    - Germany
    - Goldberg, Harry
    - Goldberg, Harry (Box 294)
    - Great Britain
    - Great Britain. Embassy (United States)
    - H - General correspondence (Box 295)
    - Harriman, W. Averell
    - Heller, Phil
    - Henson, Francis
    - Hind Mazdoor Sabha
    - Hollywood
    - Hsiao Ying (Secretary to Mao Tse-tung)
    - I - General correspondence
    - India
    - Indian Congress for Cultural Freedom
    - Indonesia
    - Inter-American Confederation of Workers (Box 296)
    - Inter-American Regional Organization (ORIT)
    - International Association of Machinists
    - International Confederation of Free Trade Unions
    - International Labor Office
    - International Rescue Committee
    - International resolutions
    - International Trade Union Centers
    - International Transport Workers Federation
    - Inter-office communications
    - Iran
    - Israel - Histadrut
    - J - General correspondence
    - Japan
    - Korea
    - Lovett, Robert
    - Il progresso (Box 297)
    - United States
  - 1952
    - British Trades Union Congress
    - Carney, Jack
    - China (Box 298)
    - Christian trade unions
    - Christian trade unions - France
    - Circulars
    - Communist Party and front organizations
    - Confederazione Italiana Sindacati Lavoratori (CISL)
    - Congress of Industrial Organizations (CIO)
    - Congressmen
    - Council Against Communist Aggression (Box 299)
    - Council on Foreign Relations
    - Cruikshank, Nelson
    - Czechoslovakia
    - D - General correspondence
    - Das, S. R. Mohan
    - Das, S. R. Mohan (Box 300)
    - Dave, C. R.
    - Department of Labor (Box 301)
    - Department of State
    - Deverall, Richard
    - Deverall, Richard (Box 302-304)
    - Dimitrov, George (Box 305)
    - Dohrn, Klaus
    - Donovan, William
    - Dubinsky, David
    - E - General correspondence
    - England
    - Etter, Willis R.
    - F - General correspondence
    - Finland
    - France
    - Free Trade Union Committee. Financial documents
    - G - General correspondence (Box 306)
    - German Trade Union Federation
    - Goldberg, Harry
    - Great Britain
    - Grenada Workers
    - H - General correspondence (Box 307)
    - Harriman, W. Averell
    - Heller, Phil
    - Hollywood
    - I - General correspondence
    - India
    - Indonesia
    - Inter-American Regional Organizations (ORIT)
    - International Confederation of Free Trade Unions
    - International Free Trade Union Center in Exile (Box 308)
    - International Free Trade Union News
    - International Ladies Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU)
    - International Rescue Committee
    - International Transport Workers
    - Inter-office communications
    - Israel - Histadrut
    - Italian-American Labor Council
    - Italy
    - J - General correspondence (Box 309)
    - Japan
    - K - General correspondence
    - Korea
    - L - General correspondence
    - LaFond, Andre
    - Lovestone, Jay
    - Lovett, Robert
    - M - General correspondence
    - Mandel, Ben
    - Manhattan Letter Service
    - Montana, Vanni
    - Murphy, Ray
    - Murphy, Robert
    - Mutual Security Agency
    - N - General correspondence
    - Netherlands (Box 310)
    - Norway
    - O - General correspondence
    - Oak, Liston
    - Offie, Carmel
    - P - General correspondence
    - Pakistan
    - Printed material
    - Procope, H.
    - Il Progresso
    - Putzrath, Heinz
    - R - General correspondence
  - 1953 (Box 311)
    - Carney, Jack
    - China (Box 312)
    - Christian Trade Unions
    - Clark, Mark
    - Communist Party front organizations
    - Confederazione Italiana Sindacati Lavoratori (C.I.S.L.)
    - Congress of Industrial Organizations (CIO)
    - D - General correspondence (Box 313)
    - Das, S. R. Mohan
    - Dave, C. P.
    - Department of Labor
    - Department of State
    - Free Trade Union Committee (Box 314)
      - General
      - Financial documents (Box 315)
    - Great Britain (Box 316)
    - International Confederation of Free Trade Unions
    - Korea
    - Murphy, Ray
    - National War College
    - Offie, Carmel
  - 1954 (Box 317)
    - Carney, Jack
    - China
    - Department of Justice
    - Department of Labor
    - Deverall, Richard
    - Deverall, Richard (Box 318)
    - F - General correspondence (Box 319)
    - France
    - Free Trade Union Committee
      - General
      - Accounts (Box 320)
    - G - General correspondence (Box 321)
    - German Trade Union Federation
    - Goldberg, Harry
    - H - General correspondence (Box 322)
    - Henson, Francis
    - I - General correspondence
    - India
    - International Confederation of Free Trade Unions
    - International Free Trade Union Center in Exile
    - Inter-office communications
    - Israel - Histadrut
    - Italy
    - J - General correspondence
    - Japan
    - K - General correspondence
    - Korea
    - L - General correspondence (Box 323)
    - Livneh, E.
    - M - General correspondence
    - McCarthyism
    - Mandel, Ben
    - Manhattan Letter Service
    - Meschersky
    - Mihkelson, Johannes
    - Montana, Vanni
    - Murphy, Ray
    - N - General correspondence
    - National Committee for Free Europe
    - O - General correspondence
    - Oak, Liston
    - P - General correspondence
    - Pakistan
    - Parmer, Norman (Box 324)
    - Philippines
    - R - General correspondence (Box 325)
    - Union of Soviet Socialist Republics (U.S.S.R.)
  - 1954-1955 (Box 326)
    - Lovestone, Jay
  - 1955
    - Deverall, Richard
    - Dimitrov, George
    - E - General correspondence
    - G - General correspondence
    - International Confederation of Free Trade Unions (ICFTU)
      - General
      - Fourth World Congress, Vienna (Box 327)
    - International Free Trade Union Center in Exile
    - Korea
    - Levine, Herb
    - Livneh, E.
    - Moral Rearmament (MRA)
  - 1956
    - Congressmen
    - International Confederation of Free Trade Unions (ICFTU) (Box 328)
    - International Free Trade Union Center in Exile
    - Israel - Histadrut
    - Italy
    - J - General correspondence
    - Japan
    - K - General correspondence
    - Kisberg, Nick
    - Korea
    - L - General correspondence
    - LaFond, Andre
    - Livneh, E.
    - Lovestone, Jay
    - M - General correspondence (Box 329)
    - Mandel, Ben
    - Manhattan Letter Service
    - Montana, Vanni
    - Moral Rearmament (MRA)
  - 1956-1957
    - Lovestone, Jay
  - 1957
    - Hungary
    - Hungary (Box 330)
    - Israel - Histadrut
    - Italy
    - J - General correspondence
    - Japan
    - K - General correspondence
    - Kisberg, Nick
    - Korea
    - L - General correspondence
    - LaFond, Andre
    - Livneh, E. (Box 331)
    - Lovestone, Jay
    - M - General correspondence
    - McDowell, Arthur G.
    - Mandel, Ben
    - Manhattan Letter Service
    - Montana, Vanni
  - 1958 (Box 332)
    - Deverall, Richard
    - Deutscher Gewerkschafts-Bund (DGB)
    - Dimitrov, George
    - Dohrn, Klaus
    - Dubinsky, David
    - E - General correspondence (Box 333)
    - F - General correspondence
    - Formosa
    - France
    - Free Trade Union Committee
    - Free Trade Union News. Publicity
    - G - General correspondence
    - Germany
    - Godson, Joseph
    - Goldberg, Harry
    - H - General correspondence
    - Henson, Francis
    - Hungary (Box 334)
    - I - General correspondnence
    - India
    - Indonesia
    - International Confederation of Free Trade Unions (ICFTU)
    - International Free Trade Center in Exile
    - Inter-office communications
    - Israel - Histadrut
    - Italy
    - J - General correspondence
    - Japan
    - K - General correspondence
    - Kenya
    - Kethly, Anna
    - Kisberg, Nick
    - Korea
    - L - General correspondence (Box 335)
    - Lovestone, Jay
    - M - General correspondence
    - McDowell, Arthur G.
    - Mandel, Ben
    - Montana, Vanni
    - Morris, Robert
    - N - General correspondence
    - New Zealand
    - Newspapers
    - Nolasco, Ed
    - O - General correspondence
    - P - General correspondence
    - Pakistan (Box 336)
    - R - General correspondence
    - S - General correspondence
    - Socialist Democratic Party of Germany (SPD)
    - Socialist International
    - Spain
    - Springer, Maida
    - Stolz, Otto
    - T - General correspondence
    - Tsiang, T. F.
    - Tunisia
    - U - General correspondence
    - United Nations
    - United Nations. Security Council
    - V - General correspondence
    - Volman, Sasha
    - W - General correspondence
    - Weiner, Herb
    - Weisman, Bernie
    - Workers Purchasing Power Chart
    - World Federation of Trade Unions
    - X, Y, Z - General correspondence (Box 337)
    - Xavier, George
    - Yugoslavia
  - 1957-1958
    - Lovestone, Jay
  - 1959
    - Hungary
    - International Confederation of Labor
    - International Film and Publications Company (Box 338)
    - Khrushchev, Nikita
    - Lovestone, Jay
    - Mikoyan, Anastas
  - 1960
    - Hungary
    - I - General correspondence (Box 339)
    - India
    - Indonesia
    - International Confederation of Free Trade Unions
    - Iraq
    - Israel - Histadrut
    - Italy
    - J - General correspondence
    - Japan
    - K - General correspondence
    - Kethly, Anna
    - L - General correspondence
    - Latin America (Box 340)
    - Lovestone, Jay
    - M - General correspondence
    - Magri, Carol
    - Mandel, Ben
    - Montana, Vanni
    - N - General correspondence
    - Newspapers
    - Nolasco, Edmundo (Box 341)
    - O - General correspondence
    - P - General correspondence
    - Q - General correspondence
    - R - General correspondence
    - S - General correspondence
    - Social Democratic Party
    - Socialist International
    - Springer, Maida
    - T - General correspondence
    - U - General correspondence
    - United Nations (Box 342)
    - V - General correspondence
    - Volman, Sasha
    - W - General correspondence
    - Windmuller, John
    - World Federation of Trade Unions (W.F.T.U.)
    - X, Y, Z - General correspondence
    - Xavier, George
    - Yugoslavia
  - 1961 (Box 343)
    - Free Trade Union Committee - Financial documents
  - 1962 (Box 344)
    - Free Trade Union Committee - Financial documents
  - 1966 (Box 345)
    - Free Trade Union Committee - Financial documents
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1919-1977 (Boxes 346-395)
  Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
  - General, 1926-1975 (Box 346)
    - Employment applications, resumes, 1967-1970
    - Family correspondence, 1924-1971
    - Greeting cards, 1954-1974
    - Invitations, 1956-1975 (Box 347)
    - Requests for interviews, information, 1954-1975
    - Retirement, 1974
      Greetings on the occasion of retirement of Jay Lovestone.
    - Thank you notes, letters, 1957-1975
  - Unidentified, 1930-1976 (Box 348)
  - ACF Industries, 1960 (Box 349)
  - AFL-CIO Labor Studies Center, 1974-1975
  - A. W. Kimber and Company, 1924-1925
  - Abbingdon Press, 1925
  - Abel, I. W., 1973-1975
  - Abern, Martin, 1925-1929
  - Abyssinian Baptist Church, 1931
  - Acheson, Dean, 1951-1969
  - Achilles, Theodore C., 1961-1974
  - Actors' Equity Association, 1970
  - Adams, Sherman, 1954
  - Aden Trades Union Congress, 1964
  - Adenauer, Konrad, 1957-1966
  - African-American Labor Center, 1969-1973
  - African Labour College, Kampala, Uganda, 1963-1964
  - Air Line Dispatchers Association, 1964
  - Der aktuelle Osten, 1958
  - Alba, Victor, 1961
  - Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn Society, 1976
  - Alexander, Robert, 1941-1976
  - Alfred A. Knopf, 1944
  - Algerian Front of National Liberation, 1958
  - All African Trade Union Federation, 1971
  - All-American Conference to Combat Communism, 1961
  - All-American Cooperative Commission, 1927
  - All-Japan Seamans' Union, 1957-1961
  - All Pakistan Confederation of Labour, 1964-1967
  - Altaffer, Thomas, 1964
  - Amalgamated Meat Cutters and Butcher Work, 1957-1973
  - Amalgamated Union of Building Trade Workers, 1966
  - American Academy of Political and Social Science, 1930 (Box 350)
  - American Adjusting Association, 1930
  - American Assembly, 1964
  - American Association for Old Age Security, 1931
  - American Bar Association, 1965-1972
  - American Civil Liberties Union, 1924-1931
  - American Committee for Cultural Freedom, undated
  - American Committee for Liberation from Bolshevism, 1956
  - American Committee on Africa, 1959-1960
  - American Defense Society, 1924
  - American Federation of Labor, 1925-1926
  - American Federation of Labor. Free Trade Union Committee, 1951
  - American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations. Publications, 1957-1974
  - American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees, 1967
  - American Federation of Teachers, 1953
  - American Federation of Technical Engineers, 1963
  - American Foreign Service Association, 1967
  - American Histadrut Cultural Exchange Institute, 1975
  - American Institute for Free Labor Development, 1962-1974
  - American Labor Party, 1941
  - American Legion, undated
  - American Negro Labor Congress, undated
  - American Political Science Association, 1941